抱歉让你久等  贝克特探长
Sorry to keep you waiting, Detective Beckett.
没关系  长官  您很忙
Not a problem, sir. You're a busy man.
这话应该对司法部长说
Tell that to the Attorney General.
他刚刚添了第一个孙子
He just had his first grandchild.
正向我炫耀照片呢
Now he wants to show me pictures.
斯塔克探员对你赞誉有加
So Agent Stack spoke very highly of you.
聪明  顽强
Smart, tenacious,
思路广阔
innovative thinker.
说你是司法部长办公室
Said you were a good candidate for the opening
特别调查员的优秀人选
on the A.G. Investigative team.
我很感谢他的信任  长官
Well, I appreciate his confidence, sir.
你不这样想吗
You don't agree?
不  长官  只是
No, sir. It's just that, um...
我是凶案组探长
Well, I'm-- I'm a homicide detective.
我没有联邦案件的经验
I-I don't have any federal experience.
司法部长不需要有联邦案件经验的人
The Attorney General's not looking for federal experience.
他要的是能完成任务的人
He wants people who can get the job done.
据我看到的资料
And from everything I've read,
你就有这能力
that might be you.
多谢谬赞  长官
Well, that's very kind of you, sir.
这不是谬赞
It's not kind.
你也是这样认为的
It's what you believe to be true,
不是吗
isn't it?
所以你今早才会坐飞机来
It's why you got on the plane this morning,
因为考虑到你的背景
because given your background,
你的资历  你的工作成绩
your qualifications, and your track record,
你知道你有更光明的前途
you know that you're headed for bigger things.
你也知道  这样的机会
Just like you know that opportunities like this
一辈子只有一两次
come along once, maybe twice in a lifetime.
但如果你不是这么认为的
But if that's not what you believe,
如果你觉得你只是个凶案组警察
if you think that you're just a homicide cop...
门就在那边
door's right over there.
不  长官  我知道我为什么来这里
No, sir. I know why I'm here.
请坐
Well, take a seat.
我们开始吧
Let's get started.
爸  我们要谈谈
Dad, we need to talk.
你更喜欢哪一个
Which of these do you like better?
爸  我是认真的
Dad, I'm serious.
我喜欢绿色的  但看起来像是
I like the green one, but it kind of looks like
巨型绿色蜥蜴在攻击城市
a giant green lizard is attacking the city,
这样很酷  但书里内容不是这个
which is cool, but it's not what the book is about.
要么我重写  把巨型蜥蜴写进去
So I either rewrite the book to make it about a giant lizard
-或者  -爸
- Or-- - Dad.
用洋红色  你是对的
Magenta. You're right.
经典  酷  符合故事风格
It's classic, it's cool, it tells the story--
爸
Dad.
-什么  -兰考斯基教授依然没收到
- What? - Professor Rankowsky still hasn't received
我去哥斯达黎加的费用支票
the check for my Costa Rica trip.
没有吗  真奇怪
He didn't? That's so weird.
你没有寄给他  对吗
You didn't send it, did you?
你为什么要去研究雨林
I'd--why--just why do you want to go study the rain forest
六个星期
for six weeks anyway?
爸  我们说过了
Dad, we talked about this.
我知道  但你会待在
I know, but you're gonna be staying
丛林深处
in the middle of a jungle,
距离最近的电话有几英里
miles away from the nearest phone,
距离最近的医院有几小时车程
hours from the nearest hospital.
你可能会被毒蜘蛛咬
You could be bitten by a poisonous spider
或是毒蛇咬
or a poisonous snake.
我查过了
I looked it up.
这个季节  巨嘴鸟特别具有攻击性
Toucans are extremely aggressive this time of year.
是因为巴黎的事吗
Is this about Paris?
鉴于最近发生的事
I will admit to being...
我的确稍稍有点保护过度了
slightly overprotective in light of recent events.
爸  我不能因为那件事就不过日子了
Dad, I can't stop living my life because of what happened.
对  我依然做噩梦
And, yeah, I still have nightmares,
但这正是我想去的原因之一
but that's one of the reasons I want to go.
我不想输给恐惧
I don't want to let fear win.
不
No.
当然  你是对的
No, of course. You're right. I'll...
我会写支票
I'll write the check.
但我不会停止担心你
But it's not gonna stop me from worrying about you
或是想你
or missing you.
我不希望你停止
And I wouldn't want you to.
只是六周而已
But it's only six weeks.
我又不是要永远离开了
It's not like I'm going away forever.
不  但看起来有人永远离开了
No, but it sounds like someone has.
你好
Good to see ya.
西托
Hey, 'sito.
贝克特在哪里
Where's Beckett?
我怎么会知道
How the hell should I know?
你们不是都同居了吗
Aren't you two practically living together now?
她有几天没来我家
Ah, well, she left me alone for a couple of days
让我写完《致命希特》  顺便说下
so I could finish "Deadly Heat", which, by the way,
这本书既致命又性感  多谢你问起
is both deadly and hot, thank you very much for asking.
我没问
I didn't.
是的
Right.
对不起  我迟了
Hey. Sorry I'm late.
还好吗
Everything okay?
没事
Um... yeah, fine.
什么情况
So, um, what do we got?
这边走
This way.
西德克旅馆相当普通
The Cedric's pretty typical.
无星公寓旅馆
No-star residential hotel.
住的人大多数是过客或外国游客
Mostly transients and foreign tourists
不熟悉旅馆情况
that don't know any better.
住客投诉说  今早开始水管流出的水
Guests started complaining of a strange colored water
有颜色  而且一股恶臭
and also a foul odor coming from the pipes this morning.
维修工最终来检查时
When maintenance finally checked it out,
发现了她
they found her.
蕾妮
Hey, Lanie.
死者是白人女性
Hey. So we've got a caucasian female.
可能20或21岁
Probably 20, 21 years old.
死因呢
How'd she die?
还不确定
Not sure yet.
头部有钝器伤痕
There's evidence of blunt-force trauma to the head.
但到验尸房后才会知道死因
But I won't know cause until I get her back to the morgue.
鉴证组在通风设备上
C.S.U. found traces of blood and hair
找到血迹与发丝
on that ventilation fan.
他们在搜索匹配结果
They're running it for a match.
这么说有人砸了她的头
So someone smashed her on the head
然后扔进了水缸吗
and then dumped her in the tank?
看起来是的
Uh, looks like it.
梯子的底部与扶手上
They found blood at the base of that ladder
都有血迹
and on the handrailing.
还有部分血指纹
Also a bloody partial print.
谁还能够上天台
Who else had access to the roof?
差不多所有人
Pretty much anyone.
门闩已经坏了几年了
The latch on the door has been busted for years,
住客经常会上来抽烟
and often, the residents will sneak up here for a smoke.
死者的身份知道吗
And what do we know about her?
旅馆经理确认她是一个住客
Building manager identified her as a resident
叫做克里斯托·斯凯
named Crystal Sky.
十天前入住18楼的一个房间
checked in 10 days ago to a room on the 18th floor.
用现金付的房费
Paid with cash.
克里斯托·斯凯  这个名字太假了
Crystal Sky? That name's so fake,
听起来像是你小说里的人物
It sounds like something out of one of your books.
说的是啊
Right?
慢着慢着  你这话什么意思
Whoa. What--what--what is that supposed to mean?
得了吧  你没听懂吗
What do you mean, what is that supposed to mean?
德里克·斯道姆  妮基·希特
Derrick Storm? Nikki Heat?
詹姆森·洛克
Jameson Rook?
你就不能编些像样的名字吗
Would it kill you to name someone Gonzales
比如冈萨雷斯
every once in a while?
尸体上没有能证明身份的物品
Well, with no I.D. found on the body,
房间里也没有包包  钱包和手机
No purse, wallet, or phone in the room,
很难查明她的身份
it's hard to know who she is.
她都来这儿十天了
Well, she's been here for ten days.
肯定和别人来往过
She must have made some friends.
是的  我认识她
Yeah, I knew her. Um...
我们有时在洗衣房会聊聊
I mean, we talked sometimes in the laundry room.
她有跟你说过关于自己的事吗
Did she tell you anything about herself,
比如她是哪儿人
like where she was from?
好像是德州人  从卢博克来的
Texas. Lubbock, I think.
但她和家里人关系不好  跟她爸处不好
But, you know, things were bad at home. Her dad.
你知道她来这里干什么吗
Any idea what she was doing in the city?
我知道她在干什么
Oh, I can tell you what she was doing.
她是个妓女
The girl was a prostitute.
她不是妓女  你为什么要那么说
She wasn't a prostitute. Why you gotta say that?
因为这是事实
Because it's true.
你看她穿着打扮
The way she dressed,
还有她房里的动静  一整晚都不消停
the sounds coming out of her room at all hours of the night--
大家都知道
We all knew it.
什么动静
What kind of sounds?
和嫖客撒欢的动静  这房子隔音不好
Her with her Johns. The walls here are pretty thin.
喂  你不知道就别乱说
Hey, you don't know what you're talking about, okay?
齐夫  我知道你喜欢她
Oh, Ziff, I know you liked her.
可现在这可怜的姑娘被杀了
But somebody killed that poor girl.
警察们必须知道事实
These folks need to know the truth.
你们最后一次见到她是什么时候
When was the last time any of you saw her?
我昨天见过她
I saw her yesterday.
晚上11点  她正要去洗衣房
11:00 p.m. She was heading for the laundry room.
有人和她一起吗
Was anybody with her?
没有  就她一人
No, she was alone.
好的  谢谢
Okay, thank you.
鉴证组刚完成了检查
C.S.U. Just finished their sweep.
他们找到什么了吗
Did they find anything?
怪就怪在这儿  没有一个指纹
It's what they didn't find. There were no prints.
好像整个地方都被擦干净了
It's like the place has been wiped down.
凶手肯定回过房间
The killer must have come back to the room
清理了痕迹
to get rid of the evidence.
好  去排查一下
All right, set up a canvass.
看有没人进出过她的房间
See if anyone else entered or exited that room.
把电梯里的监控录像
And, uh, let's pull surveillance footage
拿来看看
from the security cam in the elevator.
-也许能看到她和谁一起  -这就去办
- Maybe it'll tell us who she was with. - Right on.
哪怕不是畅销侦探小说作家
It doesn't take a best-selling mystery writer
也能猜到事实
to figure this one out.
小镇女孩怀揣美梦进城
Small-town girl with big-city dreams
结果只能卖身谋生
ends up turning tricks to survive.
是个悲剧  但这事太常见了
It's a tragic, yet all-too-familiar tale.
但是
Except...
她根本不是那么回事
That's not this girl's story.
我们用被害人的指纹查到了她的身份
We just got a fingerprint match off the victim's body.
她不叫克里斯托·斯凯
Uh, her name's not Crystal Sky.
也绝对不是德州卢博克人
She's definitely not from Lubbock, Texas.
那她是谁
Well, who is she?
艾丽卡·阿尔布鲁克
Erika Albrook.
她是哈佛的高材生
She's an honors student at Harvard.
哈佛高材生在贫民窟做妓女
Our skid-row hooker is a Harvard honors student?
还是那句话  悲剧  但这事太不常见了
Like I said, a tragic, yet not-so-familiar tale.
这不可能啊
This makes no sense.
她应该是在欧洲
She was supposed to be in Europe
和她朋友去旅游了
backpacking with her friends.
我们亲自把她送到机场
I mean... we dropped her off at the airport.
-什么时候  -上周一
- When? - Last Monday.
她就是那天入住了那家旅馆
The same day she checked in to that hotel.
你们知道她为什么会在城里吗
Any idea what she'd be doing in the city?
不知道  而且她不必住那儿啊
None. And why would she stay there?
我妹妹在市区有房子
My sister has a place in midtown.
她有什么个人问题我们需要了解吗
Were there any personal issues that we should know about?
比如吸毒  或者缺钱
Did she have any problems with... drugs or money?
艾丽卡绝不会吸毒
Erika would never use drugs,
而且她的银行账户上有很多钱
and she had... she had plenty of money
为欧洲游准备的
in her bank account for Europe.
她会不会在城里结识了什么人
Is it possible she met someone in the city,
比如新男友
a new boyfriend?
如果有  她会告诉我们的
She would've told us.
你们确定吗
Are you sure about that?
我现在也不确定了
I don't know anymore.
我只知道  我们的女儿
The only thing I do know is, our daughter
绝对不会去那种地方住的
would never stay in a place like that.
探长  这不像她啊
Detective, this isn't her.
从不闯祸的高材生
Straight-A student, no history of trouble,
梦想着去欧洲度假
on a dream European vacation
结果沦落到在三流旅馆做妓女
turns into a hooker in a ratty hotel.
这下我绝不准阿丽克西斯去哥斯达黎加了
There is no way I'm letting Alexis go to Costa Rica now.
她可能是在完美形象压力下崩溃了
Maybe she broke under the pressure of being perfect
也可能是决定
or maybe she just decided
做个改变
she needed a change.
高材生一周之内变妓女
Honors student to prostitute in less than a week?
这改变也太大了吧
That's quite a change.
是啊  说不通
Yeah. It doesn't make any sense.
对了  你今早上去哪了
Mm. Hey, where were you this morning?
怎么了
What do you mean?
我打了好几次给你
Just called you, a bunch of times.
肯定是手机没电了
Uh, my phone must have been off.
伙计们
Hey, guys.
来看看这个
Come check this out.
艾丽卡遇害当晚  晚上11点
11:00 p.m. The night Erika died.
她坐电梯到楼下的洗衣房
She takes the elevator down to the laundry room.
这是11点05分
Now this is 11:05.
她坐电梯回房间
She takes the elevator back up to her room.
看起来很正常啊
Seems perfectly normal.
是的  但你看
Yeah, but watch.
这是午夜刚过
This is just after midnight.
她坐电梯上到楼顶
She takes the elevator up to the top floor,
独自一人  但你注意看她到楼顶后的情形
Alone, but watch what happens when she gets there.
她似乎是在确认没人看到她
It looks like she's making sure no one sees her.
或者是跟踪她  但就这么多了
Or following her. But that's it.
她再没回来
She doesn't come back down.
凌晨4点前也没别人上天台
And no one goes back up there until 4:00 a.m.
在那之前呢
What about earlier?
也没有  最后一个上楼顶的人
No. The last person to go up to the top floor
也是旅馆客人  一小时前上去的
was another hotel guest an hour earlier,
但那人已经八十岁了
but the guy's 80 years old.
不可能扛着尸体爬上水塔
There's no way he's climbing a water tower with a body.
看来凶手是走楼梯上天台的
Sounds like whoever killed her used the stairs.
她的手机最近都没用过
Hey. So... No recent activity on her phone.
由于她本来要去欧洲
She left it with her parents
所以把手机留在父母那了
since she was supposed to be in Europe.
不过来看这个
But, um, check this out.
信用卡费用
Credit card charge?
是的  就在两天前
Yeah, from two days ago.
这是她入住旅馆之后唯一一笔支出
It's her only transaction since checking in to the hotel.
马格
Margo's.
是市中心一家饭店  挺贵的
That's a restaurant in midtown. It's expensive.
是的  而且她不是一个人
Yeah, and she wasn't alone.
看来她和一个叫塔利亚·麦克提的人一起付的账
Turns out she split the check with a Talia McTeague.
查一下这人  也许她那里有答案
Okay, run her down. Maybe she can give us some answers.
排查有线索吗
Uh, is there anything on the canvass?
没什么有用的
Nothing useful.
旅馆的住客都说
None of the occupants of the hotel
没见过有人出入她的房间
admit to seeing anyone going in and out of her hotel room.
不过就他们晚上听到的她房里那些声音
But given what they heard coming from her room at night,
很明显她是个妓女
it's pretty clear she was a prostitute.
她要是个妓女  那技术可真不怎么样
If she was a prostitute, she wasn't very good at it.
真的假的
Seriously?
这你都知道
You can tell that?
卖淫通常就要做爱
Prostitution usually means sex,
没有性行为的迹象
and there's no evidence of sexual activity.
但我发现了
But what I did find
防卫伤  脖子上有瘀伤
were defensive wounds, bruising around the neck,
头上有多次撞击的伤痕
and evidence of multiple blows to the head.
我猜是有人掐着她的脖子
I'm guessing someone held her by her throat
把她的头撞向通风扇
and slammed her head into that ventilation fan.
肺里没有水表明
Lack of water in the lungs indicate
她是死后被人放进水箱的
that she was dead before she went in the tank.
那又何必把她放进水箱
Then why bother even putting her in there?
水能冲洗掉证据
Water has a great way of washing away things
比如微量DNA
like trace D.N.A.
等一下  我不明白
Wait a minute. I don't understand.
如果她不是在做爱
If she wasn't having sex,
那她房里传出来的声音是怎么回事
then what were all of those sounds coming out of her room?
好吧  她不是妓女
Okay. So she wasn't really a hooker,
却希望别人以为她是
she just wanted everyone to think that she was.
为什么呢
Why?
不知道  但不是每个人都认为她是妓女
I don't know, but not everyone thought she was a hooker.
隔壁房的家伙  信誓旦旦说她不是
That guy next door, he was pretty adamant she wasn't.
他知道什么其他人不知道的呢
So what did he know that the others didn't?
我已经知无不言了
I've already told you what I know.
你还有所隐瞒  齐夫
Not everything, Ziff.
你怎么知道她不是妓女
How did you know she wasn't a prostitute?
拜托  我不想惹麻烦
Please, look, I don't want any trouble.
-是你杀了她吗  -什么  不是
- Did you murder her? - What? No.
那你说的话就不会惹上麻烦
Then nothing you say is gonna get you into trouble.
我听到那种声音
Well, I heard those... sounds, you know.
快说啊  齐夫
Come on, Ziff.
衣橱后面的墙上
There's a hole...
有一个洞
in the wall in the back of the closet.
你偷窥她
You were spying on her?
你看到什么了
What did you see?
问题就在这里  我听到那种声音
Well, that's the thing. I heard all those sounds,
但房里却完全不是那回事
but there was nothing going on.
她不过是整晚坐在床上
It was just her sitting on the bed all night,
穿着衣服  戴着耳机
fully dressed, with her headphones on,
对着电脑打字
typing on her laptop.
房里没有电脑
There wasn't a laptop in the room.
之前有的  她整晚都在弄电脑
There used to be. She'd be on it all night,
盯着电脑屏幕
staring at the screen.
你见过她和谁在房里吗
Did you ever see anyone else in there with her?
没有
No.
一直只有她一个
It was always just her.
感谢前来  麦克提女士
Thanks for coming in, Ms. McTeague.
没事  难以置信她死了
Of course. I can't believe she's dead.
你怎么认识艾丽卡的
So, um, how did you know Erika?
我们是哈佛的校友
We were friends from Harvard.
都是计算机科学专业的
We were both computer science majors.
你知道她来市里干什么吗
Do you know what she was doing in the city?
不知道
No.
但你两天前跟她一起吃过饭  什么事
But you had lunch with her two days ago. Why?
挺  奇怪的
It was... weird.
那天早上  我在格林威治一家咖啡店买咖啡
That morning, I was getting coffee from this place in the village,
正好看到她在和一个男人大吵
and I saw her in this big argument with some guy.
她的穿着跟平时不同
She was dressed very different--
十分性感  头发还是粉色的
sexed up and her hair was pink.
总之  那个男人气冲冲走了
Anyway, he storms off,
我就上前跟她打了个招呼
and I go up to her to say hello.
她一脸惊诧地看着我
And she just looks at me with this panicked look on her face
然后就跑了
and--and bolts.
晚些时候  她找到了我
Later that day, she tracked me down,
打到我办公室
called me at my office, and said
说要马上见面
we needed to meet up right away.
午餐时发生了什么事
So what happened at lunch?
她求我别告诉别人她在市里
She begged me not to tell anyone that she was in the city,
她说要是别人知道了
that if people found out,
她麻烦就大了
she could be in a lot of trouble.
她解释原因了吗
Did she say why?
我不断问她到底怎么回事
I kept asking her what was going on,
但她就是闭口不谈
but she wouldn't talk about it.
她说自己有任务在身
She said she was on some sort of a mission.
任务
A mission?
跟她吵架的那个人
This guy that she was arguing with,
你认识他吗  或者知道他们在吵什么吗
do you know who he was or what they were arguing about?
不
No.
我只听到他说
I just heard him say,
"你不知道自己在跟谁作对"
"You have no idea what you're up against."
"那些人不是好惹的"
"These people don't mess around."
能形容一下他的长相吗
Can you describe him?
能
Yeah.
警员在西德克查问此人
Uniforms are canvassing the Cedric,
不过迄今为止  还没人认出他来
but so far, nobody recognizes him.
我不明白的是  只是一整晚对着电脑的话
Here's what I don't get-- why go through all the trouble
又何必大费周章
of creating a fake persona
伪装成另一个人
when you're just gonna be on your laptop all night?
等等
Wait.
西德克有无线网吗
Does the Cedric have wi-fi?
有  也差不多只有这个了
Yeah, that's about all it has.
计算机科学专业
Computer science major,
一直对着电脑埋头苦干
hours on her laptop?
她是个黑客
She's a hacker,
所以她才去住西德克
which is why she was staying at the Cedric.
她能付现金匿名入住
She could pay in cash and remain anonymous
并用旅馆的IP地址
while she was using the I.P. Address.
没错  而且她黑的一定是
Exactly, and whatever she was hacking into
非法的或者有危险内容的网站
was either so illegal or so dangerous,
所以要确保别人不会查到她头上
she had to make sure they couldn't trace it back to her.
就算查到她了
And even if they did trace it back to her,
还得从几百个房客中把她找出来
they'd still have to find her amongst hundreds of residents.
所以她创造了个假身份
So she created a whole false persona.
谁会在意一个居无定所的妓女呢
And who's gonna look twice at a runaway hooker?
她就像是"龙纹身的女孩"
I mean, she's like The Girl with the Dragon Tattoo.
但她的确被人发现了
Only they did find her,
所以我们找不到她的电脑
which is why we can't find her laptop.
无论她对付的是谁
Whoever she went up against
是他们杀了她  拿走了电脑
killed her and took it.
有问题  我们不知道她对付的人是谁
Uh, problem. We don't know who she went up against,
而且她的朋友貌似也都不知道
and none of her friends seem to know either.
好吧  联系西德克的网络供应商
Okay, contact the Cedric's internet provider
让他们提供一份过去两周内所有
and get a list of all the I.P. addresses
所有住户登入过的IP地址清单
accessed by residents over the past two weeks.
上面应该会找到些线索
There's gotta be an answer somewhere in there.
我今天晚上不写了
How about I take a break from writing tonight,
你来我家咱们喝一杯怎么样
you come to my place, I open a bottle of wine?
贝克特探长
Detective Beckett.
能说句话吗
Can I have a word?
好的
Yes.
等会儿见
I'll catch you later?
快去吧
She's all yours.
长官
Sir.
关门
Shut the door.
坐吧
Have a seat.
我...
I,uh...
刚刚接到了一个关于你的电话
just got a call about you...
是联调局副局长打来的
from the deputy director of the FBI.
看来你今早去过特区
Apparently you had quite the interview in D. C.
进行重要面试
this morning.
长官...
Look,sir,it was--
我只是想跟你说
I just want to tell you that,um...
我给了你最高评价
I gave you my highest recommendation.
是吗
You did?
凯特  你本来就应该做这种工作
Kate,this is the kind of work you were meant to be doing.
你应该为国家效力  发挥你的聪明才智
You'd be on the national stage, utilizing all your talents.
这是个极好的机会
This is an incredible opportunity.
我像你这么大的时候  一定会为这种机会
I would've killed to have a shot at something like this
不惜一切
when I was your age.
谢谢你  长官  不过这只是一个面试
Thank you,sir,but it was just an interview.
而且希望也比较渺茫
I mean,it's a long shot at best.
我看未必
No,I wouldn't be so sure about that.
据我所知  你已入围最终候选人
From what I hear, you're on a short list.
如果幸运的话  这将是你最后一件案子
And with any luck, this could be your last case.
你吓着我了
Oh,girl,you scared me.
你这么早在这儿干什么
What are you doing here so early?
我想来看看你在受害人身上有没有新发现
I just wanted to see if you had anything new on the victim.
我能把死亡时间确定在
Well,I was able to place time of death
半夜12点到凌晨1点之间
between 12:00 midnight and 1:00 a. m.
还在她的指甲里发现了木馏油
Oh,and I found traces of creosote under her fingernails,
但这发现没什么用
which is probably meaningless
因为锅炉房就在洗衣房旁边
since the boiler room is right next to the laundry room...
她下楼的时候可能会不小心沾在手上
And it could've gotten on her hands when she went down there.
但是
But...
这不是你来的原因  是吧
that's not why you're here,is it?
好吧  怎么了
Okay. What's wrong?
现在还...
Nothing...
没什么
yet.
蕾妮  如果你得到一个机会
Lanie,if you had the opportunity
能让你做自己想做的事
to do something that you wanted to do
但是可能同时意味着...
but it would mean that...
你现有的生活将会发生重大的转变
everything in your life might change,
你会接受这个机会吗
would you take it?
这要看情况
Well,it depends.
这个机会有多好
How good is the opportunity?
很好  真的很好
Great. Really,really great.
但工作地点在特区
But the job's in D. C.
你在担心卡塞尔
And you're worried about Castle.
我们现在是在一起  但是
I mean,we're in this relationship,but...
我们从没讨论过以后
we never talk about where we're going.
现在倒是没什么  只是...
And that's okay right now. It's just...
如果我接受了这工作
But if I get that job...
那你们就必须作出决定
Then you're gonna have to.
是的
Yeah.
或许这也不是坏事
Maybe that's not such a bad thing.
但是如果是呢
Yeah,but what if it is?
卡塞尔
Hey,Castle.
没有  我就是今天想早点开工
Yeah. No,I just wanted to get an early start on the day.
我不想吵醒你
I didn't want to wake you up.
好的  等会儿见
Okay. All right. I'll meet you there.
我查了所有通过
So I ran down all the I. P. addresses
旅馆服务器登陆的IP地址
that were accessed through the hotel server...
想知道被害人在做什么
to find out what our victim was up to.
找到了吗
Any luck?
大多数登入的IP地址都是黄色网站
The majority of the I. P. s were to porn sites.
是吗  都有哪些
Really,which ones?
我直接把那些排除了
I took the liberty of ruling those out,
也排除了正常的商业网站
as well as normal commercial sites--
谷歌  亚马逊  视频网站
Google,Amazon,YouTube.
减少到了几百个网站
That narrowed it down to a couple hundred sites.
那我们现在还是在大海捞针
So we're still looking for a needle in a haystack.
也不是  我反复排查
Not necessarily. I took those and went back,
找到一些登入时间与被害人登记入住时间
looking for multiple unique site hits that coincided with the dates
相同的网站
your victim was checked in to the hotel.
还剩下20个左右
That left about 20.
这下好多了
Now we're talking,girl.
-20个我应付得来  -稍安勿躁
- I-I can deal with 20. - You might not have to.
在那20个里面  我找了一些目击者声称
Of those 20, I looked for I. P. s that were accessed late at night...
被害人在夜里使用电脑的时间段里
during the period when your witness claimed...
被登入的IP地址
the victim was on her laptop.
这个极可能就是你们要找的
This is your most likely candidate.
艾丽卡在旅馆里的每个晚上这个服务器IP
The server I. P. was accessed multiple times a night
都有被登入的记录
nearly every night Erika was at the hotel.
那这个IP属于哪里
And who's it belong to?
IP地址来自班克斯·布尔律所
I. P. was traced to Banks and Bauer.
是市中心的一家精品律师事务所
It's a boutique law firm in midtown.
为高端政客和公司做代理
Represents high-level politicos and corporations.
可能艾丽卡就像是黑客版
Maybe Erika was some kind of
艾琳·布劳克维奇[电影《永不妥协》]
online Erin Brockovich,
一个为了正义
You know,a crusader for good
挖掘法律系统黑幕
delving into the seedy underbelly of the legal system
揭露黑暗事实的战士
in order to uncover some seamy truth.
可能她只是被对手公司雇佣
Or maybe she was just hired by a rival firm
去窃取一些机密信息
to steal privileged information.
你怎么这么愤世嫉俗
Now why must you be so cynical?
我就是干这个的
It's in my job description.
这就是你需要我的原因
Which is why you need me.
好吧  你们探查一下艾丽卡的生活
Okay,why don't you dig into Erika's life?
我和卡塞尔去律师事务所看看有没有发现
Castle and I will hit the law firm and see if there's any connection.
谢谢呢
Thank you?
不  我以前从没见过她
No,I've never seen her before in my life.
班克斯女士  你确定吗
Ms. Banks,you're sure?
我很确定
Oh, I'm positive.
米切  这是我的合伙人米切·布尔
Mitch. This is my partner-- Mitch Bauer.
你认识她吗
Do you know this girl?
不认识  我应该认识吗
No. Should I?
警方认为她可能侵入了我们的服务器
The police think she may have hacked our server.
她侵入了哪里
Why, what did she access?
我们也不知道
We don't know.
-她被缉拿归案了吗  -算是吧
- Well, is she in custody? - Sort of.
算是吧是什么意思
What do you mean, sort of?
她死了
She's dead.
事实上  是被谋杀了
Actually, she was murdered,
我们认为她的死
and we believe it might have to do with
和侵入你们系统的目的有关
whatever it was she was trying to access from your system.
安保软件和防火墙
Security software and firewall protection
显示并没有过入侵
don't indicate any incursion.
但是如果黑客够牛
Yeah, but if the hacker is good,
你的软件可能检不出来
your software may not pick it up.
有没有什么方法可以查看
Is there any way to trace network activity
过去一周内服务器的网络活动
on your server for the past week?
可以
Yeah.
看  晚上11点到凌晨3点
There-- between 11:00 p. m. and 3:00 a. m.
都是上周的记录
All last week.
但根据使用日志
But according to the usage logs,
公司里没人那时候登录过系统
no one was signed on to the system at that time.
你是说  过去一周半内
Are you telling me, this girl had access
她一直在获取我们的档案
to our records for the past week and a half,
而你一直都没发现吗
and you have no idea what she was doing?
恐怕是的
I'm afraid so.
你们最近有没有
Are there any cases or litigation
什么案子或者诉讼
that your firm's involved in currently
特别依靠保密信息的
that might hinge on privileged information?
你在开玩笑吗  探长
Are you kidding me, detective?
我们是律师事务所啊
We're a law firm.
所有的案子都这样
All of them.
这么说  律所里没人
So no one at the law firm
知道她在找什么
knew what she was looking for either?
要么就是他们在隐瞒什么
Either that or they're covering something up.
唯一的证据就只在那台
But the only evidence of what she was up to
消失的笔记本电脑上了
is on that missing laptop.
没有它  我们毫无头绪[死在水中]
So without it, we're dead in the water,
像艾丽卡一样
Much like Erika.
玩笑开得太早
Too soon.
伙计们  有线索了
Hey, guys. I got something.
她约朋友吃午饭的那通电话
That phone call that she made to her friend to arrange lunch
让我很好奇她到底是从哪里打来的
had me wondering exactly where that call came from.
结果是旅馆里的公用电话
Turns out, it was a payphone at the hotel.
于是我查了那台电话的其他呼叫
So I ran down the other calls made from that phone.
有一通很显眼
One of 'em popped.
伊恩·布雷洛克
Ian Blaylock?
他以前是班克斯·布尔律所的律师
Yeah, he was an attorney at Banks and Bauer
六个月前被开除了
until he was fired six months ago.
她打过三个电话给他
She made three phone calls to him from that phone.
都超过了五分钟
Each lasting over five minutes.
这是布雷洛克
This is Blaylock.
布雷洛克先生  纽约警局
Mr. Blaylock, NYPD.
布雷洛克先生  快开门
Mr. Blaylock, open up.
事情越来越复杂了
I think our plot just thickened.
我很肯定这不是自杀
I'm pretty sure this wasn't a suicide.
你怎么知道
How can you tell?
看到脖子上这条斜向勒痕了吗
See that diagonal ligature mark running up his neck?
嗯
Yeah.
这个的确该有
Well, that's what we'd expect to find
因为身体的重量
because the weight of the body
使绳子垂直了
pulls the cord into a vertical line.
但是呢
But?
但这条浅一点的勒痕
But this other faint ligature mark--
看到勒痕沿着他的脖子是水平的吗
See how it runs horizontally across his neck?
他是被勒死的
He was strangled first.
然后才被吊了起来
Then strung up.
那这是第二起谋杀案了
So we have a second murder.
严格来说  这是第一起
Well, technically, it's the first murder.
考虑到尸温和尸体腐烂程度
Given temperature and decomposition,
死亡时间应该比水箱里的姑娘
I'd say he died at least a day
至少早一天
before our lady in the water tank.
我在查看布雷洛克的近期活动
So I was going through Blaylock's recent activity.
我发现了他
I found this chat exchange
和一个匿名用户的聊天记录
between him and an anonymous user.
"我改主意了"
"Changed my mind."
"我再也不能这样下去了"
"Can't live like this anymore."
"我要把真相都告诉你"
"Will tell you everything I know."
"在哪里见面"
"Where can we meet? "
这个人回答  "我的住处附近有个地方
The person replies, "There's a place near where I'm staying.
西德克旅馆  天台  晚上十二点见"
Cedric Hotel. Rooftop. At midnight. "
是她约他在上面见的
She asked him to meet her up there.
她肯定以为那是她的安全地带
She must have thought it was a location she could control.
看他发消息的时间
Uh, guys, look what time he sent the message.
她被害那晚的十点钟
10: 00 p. m. the night she was murdered.
但是根据蕾妮推测的死亡时间
Right, but according to Lanie's time of death,
布雷洛克那时候已经死了
Blaylock was already dead.
这是凶手发的
So this was sent by whoever killed him.
他把她引了出来
He lured her out.
又把她杀了
Then killed her, too.
律所的人坚称
So the folks at the law firm claim
他们不知道为什么有人要杀布雷洛克
that they have no idea why anyone would murder Blaylock
也不知道艾丽卡为什么要找布雷洛克
Or why Erika was looking for him.
最起码告诉了你为什么开除布雷洛克吧
Did they at least tell you why they let Blaylock go?
只说了是私人原因
Only that it was a personal issue.
肯定很严重咯
Well, it must have been pretty serious.
我们跟他的朋友谈过
We checked with friends.
显然  他是颗冉冉升起的新星
Apparently, he was a rising star at the firm
直到一年前  很突然地
until about a year ago when, out of the blue,
他变得很内向  也很离群
he just became distant and withdrawn.
婚姻破裂  开始吸毒
His marriage fell apart, and he started doing drugs.
好像是有事情发生了
It's like something happened.
艾丽卡在调查律所
So Erika was looking into the firm.
布雷洛克以前在律所工作
Blaylock used to work at the firm.
结果他们都死了
And now they're both dead.
为什么呢
Why?
刚从艾丽卡父母那里得到消息
Just heard back from Erika's parents.
他们感觉律所名字很耳熟
The law firm rang a bell.
结果发现艾丽卡高中的闺蜜
Turns out that Erika's best friend from high school
帕姆·邦纳  去年夏天在律所实习
interned there last summer-- a Pam Bonner.
好
Okay.
也许她能帮我们解决一些问题
Maybe she can give us some answers.
她在哪里
Where do we find her?
韦斯切斯特的希望山公墓
Um, Mount Hope Cemetery in Westchester.
她去年夏天死于车祸
She was killed last summer in a car crash.
当时情形如何
What were the circumstances?
没有目击者
Well, there were no witnesses,
但根据警方的报告
but according to the police report,
她当时刚离开律所的夏季派对开车回家
she was driving home from the firm's summer party.
车子失控  撞到了树上
She lost control and crashed into a tree.
尸检表示她是醉驾
Autopsy indicates that she was intoxicated at the time.
但艾丽卡不相信官方的报告
But Erika never believed the official account.
知道为什么吗
Any reason why?
她不信帕姆会醉驾
Well, she believed that Pam would never drive drunk.
警方发现帕姆时  她穿着高跟鞋
And when they found Pam, she was wearing high heels,
艾丽卡说她从来不穿高跟鞋开车
and Erika said she never drove in heels.
三条人命
Three deaths,
都和班克斯·布尔律所有关
all leading back to the law firm of Banks and Bauer.
约翰·格里森姆小说的感觉
Is it just me, or is this starting to smell like
有没有
a John Grisham novel?
畅销小说作家
大多数作品为法律悬念小说
一场没有目击者的车祸
A single-car accident with no witnesses?
这是经典的掩盖阴谋的手段
Guys, this is a classic conspiracy cover-up.
虽然她只是个实习生
Though only a lowly intern,
帕姆发现了律所正在谋划的
Pam stumbles onto something the firm is doing,
什么邪恶大阴谋
something big, nefarious.
她必须被灭口  但是事故之后
She has to be silenced, only after the accident,
布雷洛克内疚不已又不能说出真相
Blaylock can't take the guilt or admit the truth.
所以他唯一能做的就是沉溺在毒品中
So his only bastion is to escape into the sweet oblivion of drugs.
当艾丽卡找过来的时候
And then when Erika starts coming around,
他们意识到必须把两个人都干掉
they realize that they're gonna have to act by eliminating them both.
但他们在掩盖些什么呢
But what are they covering up?
不管是什么
Whatever it is,
唯一可能的证据在艾丽卡的笔记本电脑里
the only possible evidence is on Erika's laptop,
被凶手拿走了
which our killer took.
嗯  等等  我们能确定吗
Yeah. Wait, are we sure about that?
艾丽卡和布雷洛克约在楼顶见面  对吗
Erika was meeting Blaylock on the roof, right?
根据电邮  她跟这个男人并不熟
A guy who, according to the e-mail, she didn't know very well.
如果我是艾丽卡  就会把笔记本电脑藏起来
If I'm Erika, I'm hiding that laptop.
我们搜了她的房间  不在那儿
Well, we searched her room. It wasn't there.
等等  你们还记得电梯的监控录像吗
Wait. Do you guys remember the footage from the elevator?
记得  她先去了趟洗衣房
Yes. She went down to the laundry room first.
蕾妮说在她的指甲里发现了杂酚油的痕迹
And Lanie said that she found traces of creosote under her fingernails
它来自隔壁的锅炉房
from the boiler room next door.
笔记本电脑藏在地下室
The laptop's in the basement.
真是的  这明明卡塞尔的推论
Oh, man. This was Castle's theory.
为什么让我们来干这个
How'd we draw the short straw?
不知道  我问你
I don't know. Let me ask you something.
你有没有发现贝克特有点不对劲
You notice anything weird about Beckett?
什么意思
What do you mean?
她跟平时不太一样  不太对劲
Well, she's... She's different. Something's off.
你在说什么  比如她怀孕了  或者
What are you saying, like, she's pregnant or...
你在说什么啊  怎么想的啊
What are you talking about? Where did that even come from?
是你说她不太一样了啊
Well, you said she was acting different.
他们都是成年人  你情我愿的
They're consenting adults--
贝克特没有怀孕  拜托啊兄弟
Beckett is not pregnant. Come on, man.
怀孕就这么离谱吗
What's so wrong about being pregnant?
我现在完全不能跟你讨论这个
You know, I-I can't even talk to you about this right now.
那好吧
Okay. Well, um,
珍妮告诉你消息的时候  克服一下好吗
Try to get over it before Jenny tells you the news,okay?
什么  说真的吗
What? Are you serious?
恭喜你  太棒了
Congratulations, man. That's great.
谢谢
Thanks, man.
等等  上面有东西
Hold up. There's something up here.
-这是什么  -笔记本电脑
- What's that? - That's a laptop.
好的  好极了  谢谢
Okay. No, that's great. Thank you.
他们找到笔记本电脑了
So they found the laptop.
我就知道  里面有什么
I knew it. So what was on it?
硬盘被加密了  技术人员正在破解
Well, the hard drive is encrypted, so techs are going through it now.
那台电脑里藏着罪恶而致命的
Well, somewhere on that computer is a conspiracy of lies so heinous,
阴谋谎言
So deadly...
-这是什么  -什么什么
- What's this? - What's what?
登机牌
Boarding pass.
-卡塞尔  -你昨天去了特区
- Castle-- - You fly to D.C. Yesterday?
-是的  -为什么
- Yes, I did. - Why?
我受邀参加一场面试
I was invited down for an interview.
什么面试
What kind of interview?
联邦特别工作组的一个职位
For a position with a federal task force.
不好意思
I'm sorry.
你去另一个城市面试另一份工作
You interviewed for another job in another city...
却不告诉我
and you didn't tell me?
不告诉你是因为这只是一场面试
I didn't tell you about it because it was just an interview,
我知道你会生气
and I knew that you would be upset.
是的  你说对了  我很生气
Yeah. Yeah, you're damn right, I'm upset.
卡塞尔  我只想去了解一下
Castle, I just wanted to see what was out there.
这样怎么了
What's wrong with that?
问题在于你瞒着我
What's wrong with it is that you hid it from me.
事实上  你说谎了  我却不会这样对你
In fact, you lied about it. I wouldn't do that to you.
卡塞尔  这跟你无关  这是我的事
Castle, this isn't about you. This is about me.
这是我的人生
This is about my life.
所以你在认真考虑这件事吗
So you're seriously considering this?
当然  这是一次绝好的机会
Yes. This is a wonderful opportunity.
有机会做得更多
It'll be a chance to do more.
但跟我无关了
Without me.
卡塞尔  别这样  别扯到我们俩个身上
Castle, please don't do this. Please don't make this about us.
不好意思  说说这怎么能不扯到我们身上
I'm sorry. Tell me how this isn't about us?
你得到这份工作  搬去特区  我再也见不到你
You get this job, you move to D.C., I'll never see you.
我们的关系到此结束  不是吗
That's pretty much the end of our relationship, isn't it?
这可难说
You don't know that.
我可能得不到那份工作
And I probably won't even get the job.
这不是重点
That's not the point.
重点是  你知道这意味着什么
The point is, you knew what this could mean
却没有想到要跟我商量
and it didn't occur to you to include me.
或者更糟  你想到了
Or worse, It did occur to you...
但你决定不跟我商量
and you chose not to.
这说明我们到底算什么
Now what does that say about us?
要我说  不算什么
Not much, you ask me.
-卡塞尔  -我不能留在这儿了
- Castle-- - I can't be here right now.
-你还好吗  -好
- You okay - Yep.
-卡塞尔人呢  -不知道
- Where's Castle? - I don't know.
我们吵架了
We had a fight, okay?
什么  是平时那种吵架  还是
What, like a regular fight or...
有多糟
How bad?
伙计们  有发现
Hey, guys. We got something.
受害人黑进律所之后
Once your victim hacked into the law firm,
她先从基本的查起  电邮  日历  工资表
she started with the basics-- e-mails, calendars, payroll.
然后是客户和人事档案
Then she moved on to client and personal files.
知道她在找什么吗
Do we know what she was looking for?
不好说  但是在最后几晚
Hard to say, but for the last few nights,
艾丽卡在重点调查会计部门
Erika became very focused on the firm's accounting department.
会计部门
The accounting department?
看来她在查找
It appears that she was looking into
伊恩·布雷洛克的计费工时记录
Ian Blaylock's billable hours records.
重点调查的是去年夏天的一周
Focusing exclusively on one week last summer.
等一下
Wait a minute.
就是帕姆拉·邦纳车祸的那周
That's the same week as Pamela Bonner's car accident.
没错  看看这个
Right. Now check it out.
高速公路巡警确认帕姆·邦纳的车祸
The highway patrol determined that Pam Bonner's accident
发生在凌晨一点半到两点之间
occurred between 1:30 and 2:00 a.m.
而伊恩·布雷洛克在凌晨1点45分
And Ian Blaylock billed for an incoming phone call
接到一个客户的计费来电
from a client at 1:45 a.m.
所以你认为他的一个客户可能涉案
So you think one of his clients might have been involved?
也许跟她撞车逃逸了
Maybe ran her off the road?
据高速公路巡警所说  出事的是一辆车
According to the highway patrol, it was a one-car accident.
伙计们  如果艾丽卡是对的呢
You guys, what if Erika was right?
如果帕姆拉没有酒驾或是穿高跟鞋呢
What if Pamela wasn't driving drunk or in her high heels?
事实上  如果帕姆拉根本没有开车呢
In fact, what if Pamela wasn't driving at all?
开车的另有其人
Someone else was driving,
那个人撞了车
Someone who crashed
不想让帕姆的死归咎在自己身上
and didn't want to be blamed for Pam's death.
于是把她放在驾驶座上  逃逸了
So he put her behind the wheel, fled the scene.
然后打电话给律师
And then called their lawyer.
打给布雷洛克的是谁
Who made that phone call to Blaylock?
保密起见  律所用代码替换了用户姓名
For security, the firm replaces its clients' names with codes.
这位客户是47BGO
This one's 47BGO.
那家律所是不可能交出信息的
Okay, that firm's never gonna give up that information.
看看代码还有什么信息
Let's see where else that code shows up.
比照一下  看看能不能从中找到我们要的人
Cross-reference it, see if we can I.D. our person from there.
不会很费事
You don't have to look too far.
布雷洛克在车祸之后的第二天
Blaylock billed that very same client
让那个客户支付了一场高尔夫
for a round of golf the day after the car crash.
那对讨论细节来说是个好地方
Well, that'd be a perfect place to discuss details.
没有人能听到他们的话
No one would over hear them.
根据专卖店的发球员的说法
So according to the starter at the pro shop,
布雷洛克和另一个会员一起打了高尔夫
Blaylock was playing golf with another member--
科林·里格齐戴尔三世
Colin Rigsdale III.
-里格齐戴尔政治家族的人  -对
- Of the Rigsdale political family? - Yeah.
据说他父亲准备让他参选州参议员
Word is daddy's grooming him for a state senate run.
如果这件事传出来
Not if this gets out.
跟大学女生发生致命车祸
A fatal car crash with a college chick?
他的事业就完了
Nah, he'd be done.
所以他才要掩盖事实
That's why he was covering it up.
布雷洛克帮了他  但后来又开始觉得内疚
With Blaylock's help until the guilt set in.
然后艾丽卡开始做调查
And then Erika started poking around,
人们就开始死亡
and people started dying.
这里说里格齐戴尔依然由班克斯·布尔律所代理
It says here Rigsdale's still represented by Banks and Bauer.
给他们打个电话  告诉他们我要去
Give 'em a call. Tell 'em I'm coming.
好吧
Right.
发生什么了  卡塞尔人呢
Hey, what's going on? Where's castle?
别问
Don't ask.
多谢跟我见面  里格齐戴尔先生
Thank you for meeting with me, Mr. Rigsdale.
当杰西卡告诉我有人
Well, when Jessica told me someone
黑进了他们的系统时
had hacked into their system,
我当然很担心
I was, of course, concerned.
我想我们都知道我的政敌们
I think we all know what my political opponents might do
拿到了机密信息后会怎么做
if they managed to access confidential information.
那个黑进了我们系统的姑娘
So the girl who hacked into our system,
你们查出她在找什么了吗
did you find out what she was after?
是的  我们也知道了她的死因
Yes, and we also believe we know why she was killed.
你知道一个叫帕姆拉·邦纳的女孩吗
Are you familiar with a girl named Pamela Bonner?
探长  这是什么意思
Detective, what is this about?
里格齐戴尔先生
Mr. Rigsdale?
这个名字我没听过
The name's not familiar.
真的吗  我了解到
Really? I understand that
她去年是这家公司的实习生
she was an intern here at the firm last year.
是这样吗
Isn't that correct?
你去年是不是参加了
And isn't it also correct that you attended
班克斯·布尔律所的夏季联谊会
the Banks and Bauer summer associate party last year?
不要回答那个问题
Don't answer that.
探长  你在干什么
Detective, what are you doing?
和我的被害人艾丽卡·阿尔布鲁克做同样的事
The same thing that my victim Erika Albrook was doing,
试着查出
Trying to figure out
她最好的朋友帕姆拉·邦纳的真正死因
how her best friend Pamela Bonner actually died.
她的死是个意外
Her death was an accident.
真的吗
Really?
那为什么我们有记录表明伊恩·布雷洛克
Then why do we have a record of Ian Blaylock,
里格齐戴尔先生那时的律师
Mr. Rigsdale's attorney at the time,
在那晚1点45接到了他的电话
receiving a phone call from him at 1:45 that night?
探长  这是机密信息
Detective, this is privileged information.
不能作为证据
It's inadmissible.
但我们不是在法庭上
And we're not in court.
这次会面到此为止  你必须马上离开
This meeting is over. You need to leave. Now.
告诉我  我该怎么相信她
Just tell me, how am I supposed to trust her?
我该怎么跟她维持这段关系
How am I even supposed to-- to be in a relationship with her
如果她不接纳我的话
if she won't let me in?
好吧  理查德
Well, Richard--
在我们一起经历了这么多之后
After everything that we've been through together, I...
我只是不明白
I just don't understand.
我不想这么说  孩子  但我得说
I hate to say it, kiddo, but I do.
事实就是
Look, the truth is,
凯瑟琳是个聪明又有抱负的女人
Katherine is a bright, ambitious woman.
她应该去参加那份工作的面试
She should be interviewing for that job.
你到底站在谁那边
Whose side are you on?
你想让她把你放在第一位
You want her to put you first
而你们都不知道
when neither one of you know
你们的关系会如何发展
where the relationship is going.
你知道这有多荒唐吗
Do you know how absurd that is?
我是说  这跟你不给
I mean, that is as bad
阿丽克西斯的项目支票签字一样糟
as your not signing that check for Alexis' program.
这事的关键不在我
This isn't about me.
你确定吗
Are you sure?
我了解你  你不会畏畏缩缩
I know you. You do not hold back.
除非
Except...
是你跟凯瑟琳的事
This thing with Katherine.
你花了差不多三年才告诉她你的感觉
It took you, what, three years to tell her how you felt.
又花了一年才采取行动
Another year to act on it.
现在  刚出现一点麻烦  你就想逃
And now, first sign of trouble, you're ready to run.
为什么
Why?
现在你们两个很开心
Now you're having a good time, you both are,
我知道你爱她
And I know you say you love her,
但是亲爱的  她就是这样的人
But, darling, this is who she is.
所以你有所保留的原因是不是
So is it possible that the reason you have held back
因为你内心深处觉得
is because somewhere deep down inside
你们的关系不会有结果
you don't think this is gonna really work?
我猜他没有招供
I take it he didn't confess.
我不需要他招供
I didn't need him to.
我只需要看看他的眼神就知道是他
I just needed to see his eyes. It's him.
可证据不是这么说的
Well, the evidence begs to differ.
他的指纹在他十年前的一次
His prints are in the system
抗议行为中被捕后录入了系统
from his arrest at a political protest a decade ago.
我跟采到的指纹做了对比  不匹配
I ran 'em against the parti. It's not a match.
报纸上说在艾丽卡被杀的时候
And the papers put him at his family's compound in Maine
他在缅因州的家里
during Erika's murder.
好吧  他不会亲自去干的
Yeah, well, he'd never do this himself,
但雇人去干对公众人物来说又太危险了
And hiring someone else is too risky for a public figure.
他应该会让一个亲近的人
He'd... he'd get a close associate
或一个他信任的朋友去干这事儿
or a trusted friend to do it.
我们查一下他的生活找出这个人吧
So why don't we dig in to his life and find out who?
好吧
Right.
探长
Detective.
给你打电话的是副主管安东尼·弗里曼
Deputy director Anthony Freedman calling.
你还记得吗  面试你的人
You remember? From the interview.
当然  先生  我记得
Uh, yes, sir. Yes, I do.
我能为你做什么吗
Uh, what can I do for you?
你可以说"好"
You can say yes.
探长  你得到了那份工作
Detective, you got the job.
贝克特在哪
Hey, where's Beckett?
她一小时前离开了
She took off about an hour ago.
肯定有事
Something's going on,
但她不肯告诉我是什么
but she wouldn't tell me what.
我在调查里格齐戴尔的熟人的时候
Well, I was looking in to Rigsdale's known associates
发现了这张照片
and I came across this photo.
这是马丁·提利奇  里格齐戴尔同母异父的兄弟
That is Martin Tillage, Rigsdale's half brother
是家族的害群之马
and the black sheep of the family.
看起来眼熟吗
Look familiar?
是  我们询问过这个人
Yeah, we interviewed this guy.
他是西德克的一位房客
He was one of the guests at the Cedric.
他一定是为了找她而入住的
He must have checked in to try to find her
之后没急着离开
and then hung around
这样他就不会显得可疑
so his departure didn't look suspicious.
他肯定就是我们要找的人
He's gotta be our guy.
我让警员把他带回来
I'll have uniforms pick him up.
-你去找找贝克特  -好
- See if you can find Beckett. - Yeah.
听起来是个不错的机会
It sounds like a great offer.
是  很不错
Yeah, it is.
你妈妈会为你感到骄傲的
Your mom would be proud.
天啊  我也为你骄傲
Hell, I'm proud.
那你打算怎么办
So... what are you gonna do?
我也不知道  爸爸
I don't know, dad.
我觉得自己就像站在一个十字路口
It's like I'm standing at a crossroads
两种未来  我必须二选一
and I have to choose between two possible futures.
你为什么觉得你必须选一种呢
Why do you think you have to choose?
因为他是对的  爸爸
Because, dad, he's right.
如果我选择这份工作
If I take this job,
我就会没有时间给任何人
then there's not gonna be time for anyone else.
如果我拒绝
And then if I don't--
那也是为了他
It'll be because of him,
你到最后也会为此怨他
and you'll end up resenting him for it.
或者  更糟
Or... worse.
爸爸  我不知道我们之间算什么
Dad, I don't know what we have.
我不知道那是不是真实的
I don't know if it's... real.
在过去的五年里
It's like we've been doing this dance
我们就像一直在跳舞
for the past five years and...
但是曲终了  又会发生什么
I mean, what happens when the music stops?
万一我们俩爱上只是这支舞呢
What if all we were in love with was the dance?
你知道  你这辈子
You know, your whole life,
从来没有一场感情走得这么远
you've never had a relationship go this far.
走到这个地步的时候
You know, somewhere around here,
你总是结束它
you always end them.
这是为什么呢
Now why is that?
听着  凯特  我了解你
Look, Katie, I know you.
当你害怕的时候
When you get scared,
你就拿工作当挡箭牌
you hide in your work.
我只是想让你确定
And I just want you to be sure,
无论你做出什么决定
whatever decision you make,
是因为那是你想要的
It's because it's what you want
而不是因为你害怕了
Not because you're afraid.
这份工作
This job...
是我想要的
it's what I want.
那就告诉他
Then tell him.
他会恨我的  爸爸
He's gonna hate me, dad.
那就是你要承担的了
That's something you'll have to live with.
我的最后一件案子
My last case...
我得去结案了
I better go end it.
给你
There you are.
抱歉耽误了这么久
Sorry it took me so long to write it.
好好玩
Go have fun.
谢谢  爸爸
Thanks, dad.
爸爸  你还好吗
Dad, are you okay?
没事
Yeah.
你看起来有点伤心
You seem sad.
没  我没事
No, I'm fine.
只是哥斯达黎加而已
It's only Costa Rica.
我一眨眼的功夫就回来了
I'll be back before you know it.
你真好  但是  不是因为这个
Oh, that's--that's sweet, but, no, it's not about that.
是
It's, uh...
因为你奶奶说的话
something your grandmother told me.
人生总会有一刻
There comes a point in our lives
我们必须停止自欺欺人
when we have to stop fooling ourselves
明白生活不会总依照我们的意愿发展
into thinking life's gonna be the way we want it to be.
开始认清现实的本来面目
Start seeing things for how they really are.
我确实在  那又怎样
So I was there. So what?
我需要个地方落脚待几晚
I needed a place in the city to stay for couple of nights.
这也算犯罪
Is that a crime?
不算  但是谋杀女孩就算了
No, but killing a girl is.
你兄弟答应你什么了  马丁
What did your brother promise you, Martin--
尊重你这个败家子
Respectability for the black sheep,
让你在家里有一席之地
a place at the family table?
我告诉过你了  我从没见过这个女孩
I told you, I've never seen this girl before in my life.
你在浪费你的时间
You're wasting your time.
你知道有多少人
Do you have any idea how many people
坐在桌子对面对我坦白自己的罪过吗
have sat across that table and confessed their sins to me?
你凭什么觉得自己比他们特别
What makes you think that you're any different,
比他们聪明
any smarter?
你在这个房间里只待了一个小时
You've only been in this room for one hour.
但是这个房间
But this room...
这个房间是我人生
This room has been my life...
是我的家
My home.
我不会让你在我家里对我说谎
And I will not let you sit there and lie to me in my own home.
这是在凶案现场  从死者血迹里
This is a partial print found at the crime scene
提取的部分指纹
in the victim's blood.
吻合你的指纹  马丁
It's a match to yours, Martin.
我是在浪费我的时间吗
Am I still wasting my time?
我有足够的证据定你的罪
I've got enough to convict you.
所以剩下的问题就是
So the question is,
你愿意牺牲自己多少年的时光
How many years of your own life are you gonna sacrifice
去成就别人的未来
for someone else's future?
或者你愿意跟我做交易了吗
Or are you ready to deal?
他愿意供词指证他的兄弟
He's prepared to give a statement implicating his brother
涉嫌谋杀和那起事故
in both murders as well as the accident.
你们能接手吗
Would you guys mind taking it?
凯特
Yo, Kate.
嗯
Yeah.
出什么事了
What's up?
是啊  怎么了
Yeah, what's going on?
我有些事情要告诉你们
Look, there's something that I have to tell you guys,
但是在这之前  我必须先告诉一个人
but there's someone else that I have to tell first.
卡塞尔
Castle.
是我
It's me.
我们必须谈谈
We need to talk.
嗯  我们是得谈谈
Yeah, we do.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我不应该保密
I shouldn't have kept secrets.
你就是这样的人
It's who you are.
你不让别人接近你
You don't let people in.
我一直在拼尽全力地靠近你
I've had to scratch and claw for every inch.
卡塞尔  我
Castle, I--
让我说完
Please let me finish.
我一直在考虑我们
I've been doing a lot of thinking about us,
我们的感情  我们之间拥有的一切
about our relationship, what we have...
我们的未来
where we're headed.
我想要更多
I've decided I want more.
你我都值得拥有更多
We both deserve more.
我同意
I agree.
所以无论发生什么
So whatever happens...
无论你做出什么样的决定
and whatever you decide...
凯瑟琳·霍顿·贝克特
Katherine Houghton Beckett...
你愿意嫁给我吗
Will you marry me?